Are you relocating to the central Texas
area and looking for a smart way to
build wealth while settling into your
new home? What if you could live in one
side of your beautiful property and have
your neighbor pay part of your mortgage?
Well, today we'll be exploring some
really fantastic duplexes right here in
Temple, Texas. Now, before we dive in,
don't forget to like, subscribe, and
make sure you check out livingx.com
where we have some really fantastic
resources to help make your relocation
and move to the area super seamless,
including an interactive map of the area
where you can play around with where
everything is, look at some homes, um,
look at some statistics, and then we
also have that relocation guide, which
is great. All right. So, whether you are
using a FHA, VA, conventional loan, or
just paying cash, a duplex might be a
really great entry point into home
ownership and real estate investing.
[Music]
So, really cool. Well, I don't think a
lot of people realize you can use your
governmentbacked loans to
purchase one to four residential units.
So whether that's um a duplex, a
quadplex, um single family home, but in
this circumstance, we're going to be
looking at these duplexes to use your
conventional loan. It's going to be 5%
down starting. um VA you have no down
payment and then for FHA as little as 3
and 12% down and of course in this
market you know might be even better
because we're in a buyer market as of
today and may be able to get these
builders um because these are brand new
duplexes to help pay for your closing
cost maybe even buy down your rate a
little bit. So really really great
opportunities there. These are brand new
duplexes. There are currently three
duplexes on this street available um
priced under 400,000.
And what's what else is really great is
that you also get warranties along with
them. So you have your one-year builder
warranty, which is kind of like a
bumperto-bumper, and your um 10-year
foundation warranty. Another really
great selling point to these duplexes is
that because they are brand new, this
builder is offering what we call 1210
warranties. That's going to be your
oneyear general workmanship warranty.
It's the general build builder warranty.
That's kind of like a bumperto-bumper.
You move in that first year, if
something goes out or breaks, aside
from, you know, you running your couch
into the wall and denting or chipping
paint or, you know, the builder is going
to generally fix all of that. You'll
also get a 2-year major system um
warranty, which is going to be your
electrical, heating and cooling systems,
your HVAC, and your plumbing, and then a
10-year foundation warranty. So, how
cool, right? Get a brand new home, start
investing, and not have to worry about
those sort of things.
These fabulous duplexes were built by DB
Fuller Homes, and they are super modern
duplexes right here in Temple, Texas.
Each unit contains three bedrooms, two
baths with over 1,300 square ft of
living space. These duplexes are located
east of I35
off of East Adams and HK Dodge Loop.
This is a brand new community and it's
really wonderfully located in the east
side of Temple, Texas. You are again
probably an hour north of Austin, Texas,
and about 40 minutes south of Waco,
Texas.
A couple of things that stood out to me
when I was walking through these
duplexes was that there is stained
concrete throughout. There is no carpet
in the home, which will make for super
easy clean up, especially if you have
pets. And there is granite countertops
throughout as in the kitchen as well as
the bathrooms.
[Music]
You'll find fans in the main living
space as well as all of the bedrooms.
The master bedroom has an oversized
walk-in closet.
[Music]
And the master bath has a walk-in shower
with a single vanity.
The secondary bathroom has a single
vanity, a shower tub combo with tile
surround.
Something that kind of surprised me was
that the kitchen has a lot of storage,
additional storage. There's a um I guess
a pantry right inside the kitchen, but
also a oversized walk-in pantry just off
of the kitchen, whether you use that for
storage or additional pantry space. Each
unit does have its own fully fenced
backyard, which I think is a great
little benefit to these homes, as well
as full saw and irrigation. Um, and then
inside the home, you have full faux wood
blinds throughout the home, so one less
thing for you to worry about. The
lighting was fantastic
and lots of natural light in here. I
felt like the builder did a great job
with the 1300 square ft space, making it
feel very spacious. Lots of cool tones
in the paint. You have an off-white
paint and um gray toned cabinets and
accented doors with a tan colored
stained concrete floor.
[Music]
So, if you're looking for a fresh start
in the central Texas area, this may just
be your smartest move yet. Thank you so
much for watching. I'm Andrea Dudik,
your go-to guide for all things
relocation, buying, selling, and
investing here in the Central Texas
area. Whether you're looking to make a
move now or 6 months from now, you can
always reach out. You can find all my
contact information below. Till next
time.